♪～
（金角）おのれ　よくも…。
How dare you…
よくも！
How dare you!
♪～
（ダルイ）何だ！？
What?!
（みんな）うわっ！
Hey, he's exactly like the…
おい　おいおい…
これじゃあ　まるで…。
How dare you do that to Ginkaku!
貴様…　よくも銀角を！
He's just like
the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki!
まるで　九尾の人柱力じゃないか！？
♪～
What is that?
（テンテン）何あれ…。
新手か！！
There's more of them?!
♪～
（角都）金角がああなるのは
久しぶりに見るな。
It's been a while since I've seen
that happen to Kinkaku.
つまり　銀角はやられたか…。
So I guess Ginkaku's a goner.
うぅ…。
（ナルト）うお～っ！
（キラービー）尾獣チャクラの
赤青バランスもいいぜ！
The red and blue balance of
your Tailed Beast chakra looks good!
いけ　ナルト！
Go, Naruto!
いくぜ！　尾獣螺旋…。
Here I go, Tailed Beast Rasengan…
気をそらすな！
Concentrate!
うわっ！
駄目だったか…。
だが　今のは惜しかった。
Didn't work, eh.
You were close.
That's a shame!
それ残念。
なんで気をそらした！
それ勘弁！
You lost your focus!
And you have yourself to blame!
《何だ　今の感覚…》
What was that feeling I just felt?
Golden Bonds
♪～
This is really not good.
こりゃ　さすがにやべえな。
アハハ　すみません。
I apologize!
（金角）もう遅い！
（ダルイ）やっぱり！？
It's too late for that!
After all, huh?!
（みんな）うわっ！
（チョウザ）何だ？　人柱力なのか？
What is that? A Jinchuriki?
I-I owe you one…
助かったぜ…。
しかし　ありゃいったい…。
But what the hell is that…?
連合となった今　話しても
かまわんと思うから話すが…。
Since we're now allies,
I guess it's okay to tell you.
まだ　うちはマダラが
九尾を手なづけるずっと前に→
Long before Madara Uchiha
tamed the Nine Tails…
天災である九尾を
雲は　捕まえようとした。
the Hidden Cloud tried to capture
the natural calamity
known as the Nine Tails.
金角　銀角様は
そのとき　九尾に食べられて…。
During the attempt, the Nine Tails
devoured Lords Kinkaku and Ginkaku…
and then they were expelled.
九尾から出てきたとき
ああなったらしい。
Expelled? You mean from behind?
出てきたって
あれが　ケツからか！？
バカなこと言ってねえで
すぐに本部へ連絡しろ！
Don't be ridiculous! Just go and
report to Headquarters!
対応策を聞くんだ！
お　おう。
Request for instructions!
R-Right.
（シカク）増援はまだか！
Where are the reinforcements?!
ダルイ第１部隊の
戦況はどうなってる！
What's the status of
Darui's First Company?!
（いのいち）敵の主戦力の１人
銀角は捕らえられたようだ。
One of the enemy's strongmen,
Ginkaku,
seems to have been captured.
だが　金角が九尾の衣をまとって
暴れだしたと…。
But Kinkaku is on a rampage,
cloaked in the Nine Tails' Cloak!
（エー）行けマブイ！　準備にとりかかれ。
（マブイ）ハッ！
Go, Mabui! Start preparations!
Yes sir!
金角が　そうなっては
手がつけられなくなるぞ。
A transformed Kinkaku will
be uncontrollable.
（綱手）九尾の衣だと？
Transformed?
九尾のチャクラを
宿していたのは　わかったが→
I get that he has the Nine Tails'
chakra, but he's not a Jinchuriki…
人柱力でもないのに
なぜ　九尾化できる？
２週間も九尾の中にいたのだ。
They were inside the Nine Tails
for two weeks.
２人は　九尾の腹の肉を食って
生きながらえていたそうだ。
Apparently, they survived by eating
the Nine Tails' entrails.
九尾のチャクラ肉を食った者など
他にはいない。
No one else has ever eaten
the chakra-rich flesh
of the Nine Tails.
いや　正確には違うな。
No, I take that back.
これまで　雲隠れでは
八尾のタコ足を食った→
There was a fellow
in the Hidden Cloud
who ate the Eight Tails' legs.
輩もいたそうだが
人柱力にはなれず→
But he died without becoming
a Jinchuriki.
息絶えたらしい。
おそらく　あの兄弟は　特別
六道仙人の血縁にあるのだろう。
Those two brothers must
be exceptional.
They must be related to
the Sage of the Six Paths.
そんなやつを
どうやって押さえる？
Then how can we subdue him?
ひとつだけ方法がある。
There is just one way.
金角は　力もチャクラも強大だが→
Kinkaku has enormous chakra
and power.
それを封印するには
やつらの最後の宝具を→
In order to seal them,
we will take advantage of
the last of their Treasured Tools
and use it on him.
逆に利用すればいい。
ついてこい。
Follow me.
《あいつも　この瓢箪に
封印できればいいんだが…。
If I can just seal that one
in this gourd too…
それには　言霊を追い出す
幌金縄が不可欠。
In order to do that though,
I need the Kokinjo to
squeeze out his spirit word.
だが　やつの左腕にある　その縄は
九尾の衣で見えねえし→
But that rope is on his left arm
covered by the Nine Tails' Cloak.
まず　奪えねえ》
I can't get it.
ダルイ隊長！　本部から連絡です。
Captain Darui! We got word from HQ!
琥珀の浄瓶が送られるようです。
They are sending
the Kohaku no Johei.
そういうことか。
I see…
《この瓢箪よりは使えるな》
That would be better than
this gourd.
This is the Kohaku no Johei,
one of the five Treasured Tools,
（エー）これが　八尾を封印してきた
５つの宝具のうちのひとつ→
琥珀の浄瓶だ。
that was used to
seal the Eight Tails.
（綱手）瓶というよりは　壺だな。
It's more like a pot than a bottle.
（エー）紅葫蘆という瓢箪と違い→
It differs from the gourd,
Benihisago, in that…
これを持っている者の
呼びかけに答えただけで→
if the target answers the call of
whoever is holding the pot,
ターゲットの声を録音　封印する。
his voice is immediately recorded
and he becomes sealed.
金角から
こいつだけは奪ってあった。
We managed to take
this away from Kinkaku.
これを　ダルイに送り封印する！
We will send this to Darui!
戦況は　切迫しています。
これを運ぶには時間が…。
But the situation is urgent.
Won't it take long to deliver this?
雷影様　整いました。
Lord Raikage…
It is done! We can send this
to Darui anytime!
いつでも　ダルイに送れます。
マブイの術は　物を光の速さで送る
物質転送術だ。
Mabui uses
the Object Teleportation Jutsu
that transports matter
at the speed of light.
だからこそ　わしの秘書になった。
That is precisely why
she is my personal assistant.
しかし
やつらの忍具だったら→
But if it once belonged to them,
対処方法も　わかっているはずだ。
どう返事をさせ→
surely they know how to
counter this tool?
Although it will depend on how you
make him answer and seal him.
封印するかだが…。
う～む。
ならば　俺に作戦があります。
Then, I have an idea.
お前の作戦ならば
間違いあるまい。
Any strategy you come with
is sure to work.
任せる！　よし　マブイ！
I leave it to you!
Do it, Mabui!
天送の術！
Ethereal Transmission Jutsu!
《受け取れ　ダルイ》
Make sure you get it, Darui.
お互い　優秀な部下を
持っているな　綱手。
We are blessed with fine aides,
aren't we, Tsunade?
まあな。
You are right.
来た！
It's here!
（金角）あれは　俺たちの持っていた
琥珀の浄瓶。
That's the Kohaku no Johei that
was once in our possession.
そうか　そいつで俺を
封印しようというのか。
I see…
You intend to seal me with that.
《来たのはいいが
こいつのルールは　金角も知ってる。
I'm glad it's here…
But Kinkaku knows
how this tool works.
いったい　これで
どうやって封印するってんだ？
How am I supposed to seal him?
とにかく　本部の作戦だ。
Well, HQ came up with
this strategy.
それがわかるまで
こいつは　守りきる！》
Until I know what that is,
I'll guard it!
すみませんね！
捕まるわけにはいかないんでね。
Sorry, I can't afford to
let you catch me.
ダルイ隊長を死守しろ！
Protect Captain Darui
with your lives!
火遁班　放て！
Fire Style Squad! Go!
うわぁ～！
わぁ～！
水遁班！
Water Style Squad!
チッ！
ザコどもが～！
Weaklings!
土遁班！
Earth Style Squad!
ふぬ～っ！
すみませんね。
Sorry about this…
（２人）ダブル黒斑差！
Double Black Panthers!
ぐぉ～っ！
ハァ…　ハァ…。
やったか！？
Did he do it?
（みんな）うわ～っ！
ぐわ～っ！
てめえら　皆殺しだ～！
Why you—!
I'll tear you all apart!
（みんな）うわ～っ！
（テンテン）みんな　やられちゃった…。
They've all been defeated…
（テンテン）たった１人に…。
by just one man.
火　水　土　雷の
連続攻撃が効かないなんて…。
A barrage of Fire, Water, Earth
and Lightning Styles had no effect.
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
《すまない　みんな…》
Forgive me, everyone…
シカク　この術は　長くはもたないぞ。
あぁ　やってくれ。
Shikaku, this jutsu
won't last long.
I know, please do it.
《ダルイ。
Darui…
本部の　シカクだ。　聞いてくれ》
It's Shikaku from Headquarters!
Listen to me.
I've been waiting to
hear from you…
《待ってたっすよ…》
《琥珀の浄瓶は　届いたな？
You have the Kohaku no Johei,
don't you?
この作戦を　成功させるには→
For this plan to be successful,
the Ino-Shika-Cho Formation
is absolutely critical.
猪鹿蝶のフォーメーションが　必要不可欠。
それまで
なんとか　もちこたえてくれ》
Please hold on
until they get there.
Ino-Shika-Cho…
That's…
《猪鹿蝶って…。
But Shikaku and Inoichi
are still at HQ…
シカクさんも　いのいちさんも
まだ　本部なんだし…。
こうも　戦力を
大きく崩された状況で→
We've lost so many men already.
もちこたえるのは
正直　厳しい…》
To hold on is a really tall order.
Where did he go?
《やつは　どこだ！？》
♪～
（黄ツチ）ふんっ！
ぐぉっ！
黄ツチさん！
遅くなって　すまん！
Kikuchi!
Sorry I'm late!
見ろ　増援だ！
Look! Reinforcements!
♪～
Over here!
Now, we can keep on fighting!
本部の作戦だ。
It's a strategy from HQ!
木ノ葉の　猪鹿蝶フォーメーションで
金角を打つ！
We'll strike Kinkaku with
the Ino-Shika-Cho Formation.
猪鹿蝶が揃うまで
この場所を死守するぞ！
Until they get here,
we'll have to hold this location!
（みんな）おぉ～！
あいつらが　来るだと？
They're coming?
Then we can't give up yet…
こりゃ　まだ
倒れるわけにはいかんな。
《シカク：聞け　シカマル　チョウジ　いの。
Listen! Shikamaru, Choji, Ino…
今　いのいちの術で
直接　頭の中へ話しかけている。
I am using Inoichi's Jutsu
to communicate directly
with my thoughts.
今から話すことを　よ～く聞け》
Listen carefully to what I say.
（シカマル）なるほど。
（チョウジ）そういう作戦。
I see…
So that's the plan.
（いの）わかったわ。
I understand.
《二代目火影を　やっちまった
その金角とかいうバケモンを→
So we're gonna take care
of this monster Kinkaku
俺たちで　やるってんだな。
who killed the Second Hokage!
めんどくせえことになったな》
What a drag.
《なんか　怖くなっちゃったよ》
I feel a little scared.
Hey, you guys…
Don't chicken out on me.
《ちょっと　男のあんたたちが
弱腰にならないでよ！》
Legends become exaggerated
over time.
《過去の伝説には
尾ひれがついてるもんだ。
それに伝説を超えるから
新しい伝説が生まれる》
And when a legend is surpassed,
new legends are born.
うわぁ！
He may have the power of
the Nine Tails,
《あっちが九尾の力なら→
but we have the power of
the Ino-Shika-Cho bond.
こっちは猪鹿蝶の絆の力だ》
The Ino-Shika-Cho bond ranks in
the top two of ninjutsu legends.
《猪鹿蝶の連係は忍術の中でも→
１　２を争う伝説だ。　自信を持て》
Be confident!
ぐあっ！
Do not back down!
We must hold the line!
ひるむな！　なんとしても
もちこたえるんだ！
あぁ～！
ぐわっ。
うわぁ～！
また増援だ。
More reinforcements…
Sorry we're late.
遅くなってごめん。
あいつが…。
He…
How could he…?
（チョウジ）よくも　こんなに…。
Hurrah! Yes!
増援部隊だ！
Reinforcements!
– First Company reinforcements…
– Are you serious?!
第２部隊に続いて
第４部隊も到着したぞ！
and now, the Fourth Company
has arrived!
– Hey, hey…
– We can win!
おいおい　俺たち　なんか
すげえ期待されてねえか？
– Do you get the feeling that…
– The tide will turn now!
there's a lot of hope riding on us?
こんなキャラだったか？
Were we like that?
Kinda makes me nervous.
なんだか緊張しちゃうね。
ここで期待に応えなくちゃ
女がすたるわ！
Then, it'll be shameful if I don't
live up to their expectations.
猪鹿蝶って　子供の方じゃねえか。
Hey! They're the children's version of
the Ino-Shika-Cho Formation!
– Huh?!
– What?!
え？
おいおい大丈夫かよ。
Hey, can they pull it off?
ま　こんなことだろうと
思ったけどよ。
Well, I figured they'd say that.
だよね。
ちょっと　ちょっと→
Me too.
Hey, hey… A new legend will
be born here.
こっから新しい伝説に
なるんでしょ！
気合い入れていくわよ！
So let's just do it!
あぁ　わかってるよ。
うん。
Yeah, I know.
Uh-huh.
Everyone, cover them!
一斉援護だ！　クナイを投げまくれ！
Hurl your kunai!
フンッ！
この三下銅野郎がぁ！
You third-rate underlings!
どうだ。
How is it going?
ザコどもが。
You're just weaklings…
この程度で
倒せると思ってんのか。
As if you can bring me down!
（チョウジ）肉弾戦車！
Human Boulder!
Why you…
この…。
おらっ！
うわぁ！
Shadow Possession complete!
影真似　成功！
One petty trick after another…
《次から次へ　小細工を…》
《なんてパワーだ。　クッ》
What extraordinary power…
This is nothing. I can break it
in an instant.
《こんなもん　すぐに解いてやる》
影真似が　はじかれた！
He broke through
the Shadow Possession!
死ね！
Die!
ナイスタイミングだ…　いの。
Nice timing, Ino…
入った！　心転身の術　成功！
Got him!
Mind Transfer Jutsu complete!
よし　金角！
All right.
Kinkaku!
はい！
Yes!
ぐおっ！
Why you—!
この！
戻れ！　いの！
Come back, Ino!
雲に２つの光ありと
うたわれたこの俺たちが→
We, who were touted as
the shining light of the Cloud…
こんな野郎どもに。
to be taken down by
the likes of them!
Gold and silver coins may be shinier
and worth more than copper coins.
金貨も銀貨も銅貨に比べりゃ→
よく光るし価値も高えけどな。
銅貨も集まりゃ　１枚の金貨と
同等の価値になる。
But pool them together and
copper coins will have equal
or greater value than a gold coin.
同じ金でも　あんたのは
ニセモノだったようっすね。
You may be gold, but it seems
you were fool's gold.
（金角）うぅ…。
だから　俺たちが勝った。
That is why we won.
金メッキ　剥がすことになっちまって
すみませんね。
I'm sorry we peeled off
your gold plating…
いの！　ふぅ…。
Ino!
チョウジ！
Choji!
ビビってたわりには　やるわね　チョウジ。
For being scared,
you did pretty good, Choji!
冷や汗で　激ヤセした気分だよ。
I feel like I lost a ton of weight
from all that cold sweat.
気分だけなら　オーケーだ。
That was just a feeling.
You look fine, the same as always.
大丈夫　いつものお前だよ。
《作戦通りだ》
It went exactly as planned.
《よくやったぞ　チョウジ》
Well done, Choji.
《心転身のスピードと解が→
You've gotten good at controlling
更に上手く　コントロールできるように
なったな　いの》
the speed and release of
your Mind Transfer, Ino.
第６から　第１０分隊は
負傷者を後続へ！
Units 6 through 10,
search for wounded!
他は　俺に続け～！
（みんな）おぉ～！
The rest, follow me!
《言霊ってのを絞り出す縄も→
The rope that squeezes out
Spirit Words
金角と一緒に封印しちまったな。
has been sealed along with Kinkaku…
これじゃ　忍具は使えねえか…。
So he can't use the Ninja Tool.
って…　あと　もう１つの忍具
芭蕉扇は　どこだ？》
Now then, one more Ninja Tool…
Where is the Bashosen?
ん？
行くぞ　チョウジ　いの！
Let's go, Choji…Ino!
もう？
ほら　立って。
Already?
C'mon, stand up.
わ～！
あっ…　あいつは！
Th-That's…!
久しぶりだな　猪鹿蝶のガキども…。
Long time no see,
you Ino-Shika-Cho brats.
角都といったっけか…　あんた…。
You're Kakuzu, right?
金は取った。
We took the "Gold."
角のあんたの動きも
手の内も知ってる。
As for the "bishop," we know your tricks
and how good you are…
こっからは　こっちが攻め倒す。
From now on, we're on the offensive.
影を使うガキ…。
The brat who uses shadows.
お前が　ここにいるということは
飛段は止めたのだな。
Your being here means that
Hidan has been stopped, huh?
また　祈りの最中に
首でも　ハネられたのか…。
Did he get his head chopped off again
while he was praying?
それとも　あいつが
ここに　いないのは→
Or does it mean he's not here
because he's still alive?
まだ　死んでないということか…。
あいつの腐れ期限なんて知るか！
As if we know what he's doing
while he's rotting away somewhere!
フン…　飛車もなく→
So I don't have a rook,
金銀取られて　防戦一方とはな…。
my gold and silver were taken and
I'm completely on the defensive.
これで　５つ目…。
That's the fifth one.
そういえば　あいつ→
That's right…
５つの心臓があって
５回分　倒さないと…。
That guy has five hearts, so we have
to bring him down five times.
ああ…　そうだったな。
Yeah, you're right.
さて…　そろそろ　角成といくか。
Time to finish the game.
うお～！
でだ…　こちらも
金銀の手ゴマを取っててな…。
By the way…
We have gold and silver too.
そいつらは　どんなやつか
気にならないか？
Would you be interested in
who they might be?
（角都）加藤ダン…　綱手姫の相方…。
Dan Kato… Lady Tsunade's lover.
そして…。
And…
（角都）猿飛アスマ。
Asuma Sarutobi.
三代目火影の子で　お前らの師だ。
アスマ先生！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１１組の皆さんによる→